<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<!--
     Copyright 2014, NICTA

     This software may be distributed and modified according to the terms of
     the BSD 2-Clause license. Note that NO WARRANTY is provided.
     See "LICENSE_BSD2.txt" for details.

     @TAG(NICTA_BSD)
  -->

<interface label_min='SERV_METHODS_BASE' connect_ep='0'>
    <include>refos/refos.h</include>
    <include>refos/vmlayout.h</include>

    <function name="serv_connect_direct" return='seL4_CPtr'>
        ! @brief Connect to a server and establish a session.

        @param serv The anon cap to the server to connect to.
        @param liveness The calling client's liveness cap.
        @return The established connection session capability.

        <param type="seL4_CPtr" name="serv" mode="connect_ep"/>
        <param type="seL4_CPtr" name="liveness"/>
        <param type="int*" name="errno" dir='out'/>
    </function>

    <function name="serv_ping" return='refos_err_t'>
        ! @brief Ping the server. Used to easily test that a connection to the server
                 is set up correctly, also may be used for keepalive messages.

        @param session The established connection session to send ping along.
        @return ESUCCESS if success, refos_error error code otherwise.

        <param type="seL4_CPtr" name="session" mode="connect_ep"/>
    </function>

    <function name="serv_set_param_buffer" return='refos_err_t'>
        ! @brief Set the parameter buffer for given server.

        Some functions involve large amounts of data transfer, too large and inefficient to be
        transferred over IPC. In this case, we set up a shared buffer in between the server and the
        client.

        Note that the server may or may not support setting internal or external dataspaces as the
        parameter buffer. The user should check with the documentation for the server. An internal
        dataspace here means that the server is itself a dataserver, and setting the server's own
        dataspace as the parameter buffer. External here means that the dataspace being used as the
        parameter buffer here comes from another dataspace server.

        @param session The established connection session to set param buffer for.
        @param parambuffer_dataspace The dataspace to set as param buffer. May be internal or external.
        @param parambuffer_size The size of the parameter buffer to set up.
        @return ESUCCESS if success, refos_error error code otherwise.

        <param type="seL4_CPtr" name="session" mode="connect_ep"/>
        <param type="seL4_CPtr" name="parambuffer_dataspace"/>
        <param type="uint32_t" name="parambuffer_size"/>
    </function>

    <function name="serv_disconnect_direct" return='void'>
        ! @brief Disconnect from a server.
        @param session The established connection session to disconnect.

        <param type="seL4_CPtr" name="session" mode="connect_ep"/>
    </function>

</interface>